My second story is about love and loss.
I was lucky I found what I loved to do early in life.
Woz and I started Apple in my parents garage when I was 20.
We worked hard, and in 10 years Apple had grown from just the two of
us in a garage into a $2 billion company with over 4000 employees.
We had just released our finest creation the Macintosh
a year earlier, and I had just turned 30.
And then I got fired.
How can you get fired from a company you started?
Well, as Apple grew we hired someone who I thought
was very talented to run the company with me,
and for the first year or so things went well.
But then our visions of the future began
to diverge and eventually we had a falling out.
When we did, our Board of Directors sided with him.
So at 30 I was out. And very publicly out.
What had been the focus of my entire adult life was gone,
and it was devastating.
I really didn't know what to do for a few months.
I felt that I had let the previous generation of entrepreneurs
down - that I had dropped the baton as it was being passed to me.
I met with David Packard and Bob Noyce
and tried to apologize for screwing up so badly.
I was a very public failure,
and I even thought about running away from the valley.
But something slowly began to dawn on me I still loved what I did.
The turn of events at Apple had not changed that one bit.
I had been rejected, but I was still in love.
And so I decided to start over.
I didn't see it then, but it turned out that getting fired from
Apple was the best thing that could have ever happened to me.
The heaviness of being successful was
replaced by the lightness of being a beginner again,
less sure about everything.
It freed me to enter one of the most creative periods of my life.
During the next five years, I started a company named NeXT,
another company named Pixar,
and fell in love with an amazing woman who would become my wife.
Pixar went on to create the worlds first computer animated feature
film, Toy Story,
and is now the most successful animation studio in the world.
In a remarkable turn of events, Apple bought NeXT,
I returned to Apple, and the technology we developed at
NeXT is at the heart of Apple's current renaissance.
And Laurene and I have a wonderful family together.
I'm pretty sure none of this would
have happened if I hadn't been fired from Apple.
It was awful tasting medicine, but I guess the patient needed it.
Sometimes life hits you in the head with a brick. Don't lose faith.
I'm convinced that the only thing that kept me going was that I loved
what I did. You've got to find what you love.
And that is as true for your work as it is for your lovers.
Your work is going to fill a large part of your life,
and the only way to be truly satisfied
is to do what you believe is great work.
And the only way to do great work is to love what you do.
If you haven't found it yet, keep looking. Don't settle.
As with all matters of the heart, you'll know when you find it.
And, like any great relationship,
it just gets better and better as the years roll on.
So keep looking. Don't settle.
My third story is about death.
When I was 17, I read a quote that went something like:
"If you live each day as if it was your last,
someday you'll most certainly be right."
It made an impression on me, and since then, for the past 33 years,
I have looked in the mirror every morning
and asked myself: "If today were the last day of my life,
would I want to do what I am about to do today?"
And whenever the answer has been "No" for too many days in a row,
I know I need to change something.
Remembering that I'll be dead soon is the most important
tool I've ever encountered to help me make the big choices in life.
Because almost everything all external expectations, all pride,
all fear of embarrassment or failure -
these things just fall away in the face of death,
leaving only what is truly important.
Remembering that you are going to die is the best
way I know to avoid the trap of thinking you have something to lose.
You are already naked. There is no reason not to follow your heart.
About a year ago I was diagnosed with cancer.
I had a scan at 7:30 in the morning,
and it clearly showed a tumor on my pancreas.
I didn't even know what a pancreas was.
The doctors told me this was almost
certainly a type of cancer that is incurable,
and that I should expect to live no longer than three to six months.
My doctor advised me to go home and get my affairs in order,
which is doctor's code for prepare to die.
It means to try to tell your kids everything you thought
you'd have the next 10 years to tell them in just a few months.
It means to make sure everything is buttoned
up so that it will be as easy as possible for your family.
It means to say your goodbyes.
I lived with that diagnosis all day.
Later that evening I had a biopsy,
where they stuck an endoscope down my throat,
through my stomach and into my intestines,
put a needle into my pancreas and got a few cells from the tumor.
I was sedated, but my wife, who was there,
told me that when they viewed the cells under a microscope
the doctors started crying because it turned out to be
a very rare form of pancreatic cancer that is curable with surgery.
I had the surgery and thankfully I'm fine now.
This was the closest I've been to facing death,
and I hope its the closest I get for a few more decades.
Having lived through it,
I can now say this to you with a bit more certainty than when
death was a useful but purely intellectual concept:
No one wants to die.
Even people who want to go to heaven don't want to die to get there.
And yet death is the destination we all share.
No one has ever escaped it. And that is as it should be,
because Death is very likely the single best invention of Life.
It is Life's change agent.
It clears out the old to make way for the new.
Right now the new is you, but someday not too long from now,
you will gradually become the old and be cleared away.
Sorry to be so dramatic, but it is quite true.
Your time is limited, so don't waste it living someone else's life.
Don't be trapped by dogma which is living
with the results of other people's thinking.
Don't let the noise of others' opinions drown out your own inner
voice. And most important,
have the courage to follow your heart and intuition.
They somehow already know what you truly want to become.
Everything else is secondary.
When I was young,
there was an amazing publication called The Whole Earth Catalog,
which was one of the bibles of my generation.
It was created by a fellow named Stewart Brand not far from here
in Menlo Park, and he brought it to life with his poetic touch.
This was in the late 1960's,
before personal computers and desktop publishing,
so it was all made with typewriters, scissors, and polaroid cameras.
It was sort of like Google in paperback form,
35 years before Google came along: it was idealistic,
overflowing with neat tools, and great notions.
Stewart and his team put out several
issues of The Whole Earth Catalog,
and then when it had run its course, they put out a final issue.
It was the mid-1970s, and I was your age.
On the back cover of their final issue
was a photograph of an early morning country road,
the kind you might find yourself
hitchhiking on if you were so adventurous.
Beneath it were the words: "Stay Hungry. Stay Foolish."
It was their farewell message as they signed off. Stay Hungry.
Stay Foolish. And I have always wished that for myself.
And now, as you graduate to begin anew, I wish that for you.
Stay Hungry. Stay Foolish.
Thank you all very much.
The preceding program is copyrighted by Stanford University.
Please visit us at stanford.edu