This program is brought to you by Stanford University.
Please visit us at stanford.edu
Thank You. I am honored to be with you today at your commencement
from one of the finest universities in the world.
Truth be told I never graduated from college
and this is the closest I've ever gotten to a college graduation.
Today I want to tell you three stories from my life. That's it.
No big deal. Just three stories.
The first story is about connecting the dots.
I dropped out of Reed College after the first 6 months,
but then stayed around as a drop-in
for another 18 months or so before I really quit.
So why did I drop out?
It started before I was born.
My biological mother was a young, unwed graduate student,
and she decided to put me up for adoption.
She felt very strongly that I should be adopted by college graduates,
so everything was all set for me to
be adopted at birth by a lawyer and his wife.
Except that when I popped out they decided
at the last minute that they really wanted a girl.
So my parents, who were on a waiting list,
got a call in the middle of the night asking: "We have an unexpected
baby boy; do you want him?"
They said: "Of course." My biological mother later found out that
my mother had never graduated from college
and that my father had never graduated from high school.
She refused to sign the final adoption papers.
She only relented a few months later when
my parents promised that I would go to college. This was the start in my life.
And 17 years later I did go to college. But I naively chose a college
that was almost as expensive as Stanford,
and all of my working-class parents'
savings were being spent on my college tuition.
After six months, I couldn't see the value in it.
I had no idea what I wanted to do with my life
and no idea how college was going to help me figure it out.
And here I was spending all of the money my parents had saved
their entire life.
So I decided to drop out and trust that it would all work out OK.
It was pretty scary at the time,
but looking back it was one of the best decisions I ever made.
The minute I dropped out I could stop
taking the required classes that didn't interest me,
and begin dropping in on the ones that looked interesting.
It wasn't all romantic. I didn't have a dorm room,
so I slept on the floor in friends' rooms,
I returned coke bottles for the 5 cent deposits to buy food with,
and I would walk the 7 miles across town every Sunday
night to get one good meal a week at the Hare Krishna
temple. I loved it.
And much of what I stumbled into by following
my curiosity and intuition turned out to be priceless later on.
Let me give you one example: Reed College at that
time offered perhaps the best calligraphy instruction in the country.
Throughout the campus every poster, every label on every drawer,
was beautifully hand calligraphed.
Because I had dropped out and didn't have to take the normal classes,
I decided to take a calligraphy class to learn how to do this.
I learned about serif and san serif typefaces,
about varying the amount of space
between different letter combinations,
about what makes great typography great.
It was beautiful, historical,
artistically subtle in a way that science can't capture,
and I found it fascinating.
None of this had even a hope of any practical application in my life.
But ten years later,
when we were designing the first Macintosh computer,
it all came back to me. And we designed it all into the Mac.
It was the first computer with beautiful typography.
If I had never dropped in on that single course in college,
the Mac would have never had multiple
typefaces or proportionally spaced fonts.
And since Windows just copied the Mac,
it's likely that no personal computer would have them.
If I had never dropped out,
I would have never dropped in on this calligraphy class,
and personal computers might not have the wonderful typography
that they do. Of course it was impossible to connect
the dots looking forward when I was in college.
But it was very, very clear looking backwards ten years later.
Again, you can't connect the dots looking forward;
you can only connect them looking backwards.
So you have to trust that the dots will somehow connect
in your future.
You have to trust in something, your gut, destiny, life, karma,
whatever.
Beleiveing that the dots will connect down the road will give you the confidence to follow your heart
Even when it leads you off the well worn path, and that will make all the difference.