President Faust, Board of Overseers, faculty, alumni, friends, proud parents, members of
the ad board, and graduates of the greatest university in the world,
I'm honored to be with you today because, let's face it, you accomplished something
I never could.
If I get through this speech, it'll be the first time I actually finish something at
Harvard.
Class of 2017, congratulations!
I'm an unlikely speaker, not just because I dropped out, but because we're technically
in the same generation.
We walked this yard less than a decade apart, studied the same ideas and slept through the
same Ec10 lectures.
We may have taken different paths to get here, especially if you came all the way from the
Quad, but today I want to share what I've learned about our generation and the world
we're building together.
But first, the last couple of days have brought back a lot of good memories.
How many of you remember exactly what you were doing when you got that email telling
you that you got into Harvard?
I was playing Civilization and I ran downstairs, got my dad, and for some reason, his reaction
was to video me opening the email.
That could have been a really sad video.
I swear getting into Harvard is still the thing my parents are most proud of me for.
What about  your first lecture at Harvard?
Mine was Computer Science 121 with the incredible Harry Lewis.
I was late so I threw on a t-shirt and didn't realize until afterwards it was inside out
and backwards with my tag sticking out the front.
I couldn't figure out why no one would talk to me -- except one guy, KX Jin, he just went
with it.
We ended up doing our problem sets together, and now he runs a big part of Facebook.
And that, Class of 2017, is why you should be nice to people.
But my best memory from Harvard was meeting Priscilla.
I had just launched this prank website Facemash, and the ad board wanted to "see me".
Everyone thought I was going to get kicked out.
My parents came to help me pack.
My friends threw me a going away party.
As luck would have it, Priscilla was at that party with her friend.
We met in line for the bathroom in the Pfoho Belltower, and in what must be one of the
all time romantic lines, I said: "I'm going to get kicked out in three days, so we need
to go on a date quickly."
Actually, any of you graduating can use that line.
I didn't end up getting kicked out -- I did that to myself.
Priscilla and I started dating.
And, you know, that movie made it seem like Facemash was so important to creating Facebook.
It wasn't.
But without Facemash I wouldn't have met Priscilla, and she's the most important person in my
life, so you could say it was the most important thing I built in my time here.
We've all started lifelong friendships here, and some of us even families.
That's why I'm so grateful to this place.
Thanks, Harvard.
Today I want to talk about purpose.