Today I want to talk about three ways to create a world where everyone has a sense of purpose:
by taking on big meaningful projects together, by redefining equality so everyone has the
freedom to pursue purpose, and by building community across the world.
First, let's take on big meaningful projects.
Our generation will have to deal with tens of millions of jobs replaced by automation
like self-driving cars and trucks.
But we have the potential to do so much more together.
Every generation has its defining works.
More than 300,000 people worked to put a man on the moon \'96 including that janitor.
Millions of volunteers immunized children around the world against polio.
Millions of more people built the Hoover dam and other great projects.
These projects didn't just provide purpose for the people doing those jobs, they gave
our whole country a sense of pride that we could do great things.
Now it's our turn to do great things.
I know, you're probably thinking: I don't know how to build a dam, or get a million
people involved in anything.
But let me tell you a secret: no one does when they begin.
Ideas don't come out fully formed.
They only become clear as you work on them.
You just have to get started.
If I had to understand everything about connecting people before I began, I never would have
started Facebook.
Movies and pop culture get this all wrong.
The idea of a single eureka moment is a dangerous lie.
It makes us feel inadequate since we haven't had ours.
It prevents people with seeds of good ideas from getting started.
Oh, you know what else movies get wrong about innovation?
No one writes math formulas on glass.
That's not a thing.
It's good to be idealistic.
But be prepared to be misunderstood.
Anyone working on a big vision will get called crazy, even if you end up right.
Anyone working on a complex problem will get blamed for not fully understanding the challenge,
even though it's impossible to know everything upfront.
Anyone taking initiative will get criticized for moving too fast, because there's always
someone who wants to slow you down.
In our society, we often don't do big things because we're so afraid of making mistakes
that we ignore all the things wrong today if we do nothing.
The reality is, anything we do will have issues in the future.
But that can't keep us from starting.
So what are we waiting for?
It's time for our generation-defining public works.
How about stopping climate change before we destroy the planet and getting millions of
people involved manufacturing and installing solar panels?
How about curing all diseases and asking volunteers to track their health data and share their
genomes?
Today we spend 50x more treating people who are sick than we spend finding cures so people
don't get sick in the first place.
That makes no sense.
We can fix this.
How about modernizing democracy so everyone can vote online, and personalizing education
so everyone can learn?
These achievements are within our reach.
Let's do them all in a way that gives everyone in our society a role.
Let's do big things, not only to create progress, but to create purpose.
So taking on big meaningful projects is the first thing we can do to create a world where
everyone has a sense of purpose.
The second is redefining equality to give everyone the freedom they need to pursue purpose.
Many of our parents had stable jobs throughout their careers.
Now we're all entrepreneurial, whether we're starting projects or finding or role.
And that's great.
Our culture of entrepreneurship is how we create so much progress.
Now, an entrepreneurial culture thrives when it's easy to try lots of new ideas.
Facebook wasn't the first thing I built.
I also built games, chat systems, study tools and music players.
I'm not alone.
JK Rowling got rejected 12 times before publishing Harry Potter.
Even Beyonce had to make hundreds of songs to get Halo.
The greatest successes come from having the freedom to fail.
But today, we have a level of wealth inequality that hurts everyone.
When you don't have the freedom to take your idea and turn it into a historic enterprise,
we all lose.
Right now our society is way over-indexed on rewarding success and we don't do nearly
enough to make it easy for everyone to take lots of shots.
Let's face it.
There is something wrong with our system when I can leave here and make billions of dollars
in 10 years while millions of students can't afford to pay off their loans, let alone start
a business.
Look, I know a lot of entrepreneurs, and I don't know a single person who gave up on
starting a business because they might not make enough money.
But I know lots of people who haven't pursued dreams because they didn't have a cushion
to fall back on if they failed.
We all know we don't succeed just by having a good idea or working hard.
We succeed by being lucky too.
If I had to support my family growing up instead of having time to code, if I didn't know I'd
be fine if Facebook didn't work out, I wouldn't be standing here today.
If we're honest, we all know how much luck we've had.
Every generation expands its definition of equality.
Previous generations fought for the vote and civil rights.
They had the New Deal and Great Society.
Now it's our time to define a new social contract for our generation.
We should have a society that measures progress not just by economic metrics like GDP, but
by how many of us have a role we find meaningful.
We should explore ideas like universal basic income to give everyone a cushion to try new
things.
We\'92re going to change jobs many times, so we need affordable childcare to get to
work and healthcare that aren't tied to one company.
We're all going to make mistakes, so we need a society that focuses less on locking us
up or stigmatizing us.
And as technology keeps changing, we need to focus more on continuous education throughout
our lives.\ And yes, giving everyone the freedom to pursue
purpose isn't free.
People like me should pay for it.
Many of you will do well and you should too.
That's why Priscilla and I started the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative and committed our wealth
to promoting equal opportunity.
These are the values of our generation.
It was never a question of if we were going to do this.
The only question was when.
Millennials are already one of the most charitable generations in history.
In one year, three of four US millennials made a donation and seven out of ten raised
money for charity.
But it's not just about money.
You can also give time.
I promise you, if you take an hour or two a week -- that's all it takes to give someone
a hand, to help them reach their potential.
Maybe you think that's too much time.
I used to.
When Priscilla graduated from Harvard she became a teacher, and before she'd do education
work with me, she told me I needed to teach a class.
I complained: "Well, I'm kind of busy.
I'm running this company."
But she insisted, so I taught a middle school program on entrepreneurship at the local Boys
and Girls Club.
I taught them lessons on product development and marketing, and they taught me what it's
like feeling targeted for your race and having a family member in prison.
I shared stories from my time in school, and they shared their hope of one day going to
college too.
For five years now, I\'92ve been having dinner with those kids every month.
One of them threw me and Priscilla our first baby shower.
And next year they\'92re going to college.
Every one of them.
First in their families.
We can all make time to give someone a hand.
Let's give everyone the freedom to pursue their purpose -- not only because it's the
right thing to do, but because when more people can turn their dreams into something great,
we're all better for it.