Purpose doesn't only come from work.
The third way we can create a sense of purpose for everyone is by building community.
And when our generation says "everyone", we mean everyone in the world.
Quick show of hands: how many of you are from another country?
Now, how many of you are friends with one of these folks?
Now we're talking.
We have grown up connected.\ In a survey asking millennials around the
world what defines our identity, the most popular answer wasn't nationality, religion
or ethnicity, it was "citizen of the world".
That's a big deal.
Every generation expands the circle of people we consider "one of us".
For us, it now encompasses the entire world.
We understand the great arc of human history bends towards people coming together in ever
greater numbers -- from tribes to cities to nations -- to achieve things we couldn't on
our own.
We get that our greatest opportunities are now global -- we can be the generation that
ends poverty, that ends disease.
We get that our greatest challenges need global responses too -- no country can fight climate
change alone or prevent pandemics.
Progress now requires coming together not just as cities or nations, but also as a global
community.
But we live in an unstable time.
There are people left behind by globalization across the world.
It's hard to care about people in other places if we don't feel good about our lives here
at home.
There's pressure to turn inwards.
This is the struggle of our time.
The forces of freedom, openness and global community against the forces of authoritarianism,
isolationism and nationalism.
Forces for the flow of knowledge, trade and immigration against those who would slow them
down.
This is not a battle of nations, it's a battle of ideas.
There are people in every country for global connection and good people against it.
This isn't going to be decided at the UN either.
It's going to happen at the local level, when enough of us feel a sense of purpose and stability
in our own lives that we can open up and start caring about everyone.
The best way to do that is to start building local communities right now.
We all get meaning from our communities.
Whether our communities are houses or sports teams, churches or music groups, they give
us that sense we are part of something bigger, that we are not alone; they give us the strength
to expand our horizons.
That's why it's so striking that for decades, membership in all kinds of groups has declined
as much as one-quarter.
That's a lot of people who now need to find purpose somewhere else.
But I know we can rebuild our communities and start new ones because many of you already
are.
I met Agnes Igoye, who's graduating today.
Where are you, Agnes?
She spent her childhood navigating conflict zones in Uganda, and now she trains thousands
of law enforcement officers to keep communities safe.
I met Kayla Oakley and Niha Jain, graduating today, too.
Stand up.
Kayla and Niha started a non-profit that connects people suffering from illnesses with people
in their communities willing to help.
I met David Razu Aznar, graduating from the Kennedy School today.
David, stand up.
He's a former city councilor who successfully led the battle to make Mexico City the first
Latin American city to pass marriage equality -- even before San Francisco.
This is my story too.
A student in a dorm room, connecting one community at a time, and keeping at it until one day
we connect the whole world.
Change starts local.
Even global changes start small -- with people like us.
In our generation, the struggle of whether we connect more, whether we achieve our biggest
opportunities, comes down to this -- your ability to build communities and create a
world where every single person has a sense of purpose.
Class of 2017, you are graduating into a world that needs purpose.
It's up to you to create it.
Now, you may be thinking: can I really do this?
Remember when I told you about that class I taught at the Boys and Girls Club?
One day after class I was talking to them about college, and one of my top students
raised his hand and said he wasn't sure he could go because he's undocumented.
He didn't know if they'd let him in.
Last year I took him out to breakfast for his birthday.
I wanted to get him a present, so I asked him and he started talking about students
he saw struggling and said "You know, I'd really just like a book on social justice."
I was blown away.
Here's a young guy who has every reason to be cynical.
He didn't know if the country he calls home -- the only one he's known -- would deny him
his dream of going to college.
But he wasn't feeling sorry for himself.
He wasn't even thinking of himself.
He has a greater sense of purpose, and he's going to bring people along with him.
It says something about our current situation that I can't even say his name because I don't
want to put him at risk.
But if a high school senior who doesn't know what the future holds can do his part to move
the world forward, then we owe it to the world to do our part too.
Before you walk out those gates one last time, as we sit in front of Memorial Church, I am
reminded of a prayer, Mi Shebeirach, that I say whenever I face a challenge, that I
sing to my daughter thinking about her future when I tuck her into bed.
It goes: "May the source of strength, who blessed the
ones before us, help us *find the courage* to make our lives a blessing."
I hope you find the courage to make your life a blessing.
Congratulations, Class of '17!
Good luck out there.